Declan Greenhalgh

https://www.declangreenhalgh.com

Who I am

I am an engineering manager who works at UBS within the Exchange Traded Derivatives Clearing area, managing a small team delivering message transformation capabilities within a Next Gen programme. I have previously worked for Tesco, in the online search space, Rightmove, in the Data Services Team, ION Trading (in the FX space), and NatWest Markets (formerly RBS M&IB, within the Futures space). I have worked on both large-scale re-engineering projects, as well as smaller bespoke applications. Whilst I mainly work in Java 8 & 11, I am equally keen on working with Python and .NET technologies.

I have followed an atypical route into software development/management, having come from a psychology background prior to my computer science education. This background complements my skills in software engineering and management, with my main interests being in organisational capabilities, Agile practices and development processes - all contributing to regular delivery of high value change.

I am always keen on adding more skills to my repertoire, and aim to continue my growth as a well rounded engineer/lead with the confidence to tackle any challenge. I enjoy delivering holistic solutions and contributing to my teams in every way I can, be it through programming, analysis, design, support or stakeholder engagement.

Employment

UBS AG.

IT Service Delivery Manager - Associate Director (April '21 - Present)

- > Engineering-oriented management role, covering technical, people and project management.
- > Project management of a multi-year re-engineering project, owning the Transformation stream.
- > Implementing a message transformation capability and providing tooling to empower IT and business users across the bank to manage various transformations, across a variety of protocols.
- > Utilisation of various Azure components, for delivery of Kubernetes-orchestrated applications.
- > Engagement with project management teams, providing regular presentations and status updates.
- > Interviewing external candidates for UBS engineering roles.
- > SME on a number of working groups looking at enhancing technology across the organisation and removing impediments to high-performance delivery.

Tesco Plc.

Software Development Engineer II (April '20 - April '21)

- Continuation of backend-focused work, utilising Java 8 and 11.
- > Specifically worked on more infrastructure-related projects, utilising Kubernetes in AWS and Azure environments.
- Supporting legacy data ingestion applications using Apache Camel and Elasticsearch.
- > Spearheaded integrations with new Enterprise APIs, and worked directly with product teams to introduce new functionality on the Tesco site.

Rightmove Plc.

Developer (October '18 - April '20)

- Backend-focused developer working on applications supporting property science.
- Working on Java versions 7, 8 and 11 developing Microservices.
- > Creating Python 3 microservices for application of machine learning models, using Flask APIs and Sklearn.
- Introduction of Elasticsearch to support more data-heavy projects across the business, as well as minor use of Kafka for ingestion and production of events.
- > Some front-end development in AngularJS and React.
- Utilisation of Spring Frameworks (inc. Spring Boot) and Docker.
- > Expanded testing knowledge using Cucumber and Selenium for functional testing, and Pact for Consumer Driven Contracts.
- Worked with external stakeholders, including application demos and requirements gathering.

Email: dec@decln.com

ION Trading Ltd.

Developer (February '18 - September '18)

- ➤ Worked on a large-scale FX trade management re-engineering project.
- Primarily used Java 8.
- Use of ATDD (Robot Framework) and mocking frameworks (Mockito).
- > Utilised dependency injection frameworks (Guice), and Spring Hibernate.
- > Focused on the delivery of a post-trade solution with an emphasis on service-oriented architecture.
- > Gained experience working with larger Agile teams using the LeSS framework.

NatWest Markets (Royal Bank of Scotland Group)

Application Manager / Developer - Associate (September '17 - February '18)

- > A continuation of the below role, in a permanent capacity.
- > An increased focus on application design, project management, stakeholder management, and providing services as the application SME.
- > Worked on the implementation of various MiFID II project deliverables.

MThree Consulting Ltd / NatWest Markets

Developer (September '15 - September '17)

- > Worked primarily in an application management/developer role in the Futures Technology space.
- ➤ Day-to-day was working on the in-house Futures Execution & Clearing Order Management System that handles execution and allocation routing between the full F2B stack. Previously worked on a major transformation project due to a 3rd-party vendor switch, working on the entire lifecycle in an agile environment.
- > Have been responsible for the implementation of CMMI within my application.
- > Technologies used include Java 7, FIX Protocol, Oracle SQL, Unix, TIBCO EMS, IBM MQ and a variety of agile tools.
- Obtained an ITIL 4 Foundation certificate in IT service management.

University of Kent Information Services

Assistant Support Desk Supervisor (September 2014 – August 2015)

- Role included supervisory & SME aspects.
- > Required to manage the University IT services at the weekend and out of hours.

IT and Library Support Desk Assistant (April 2013 – September 2014)

- Customer-facing helpdesk role helping with technical issues.
- > Helped develop my abilities to deal with a range of customers, communicating with relevant colleagues and maintaining a presentable, professional work environment.

Education

MSc. Computer Science, University of Kent, 2014 - 2015

Obtained a Master's degree in a programme covering a wide range of computing concepts, including: Java-based Object Oriented Programming, Web-Based Information Systems, Logic Programming, Machine Learning and Systems Architecture.

BSc. (Hons.) Psychology and Sociology, University of Kent, 2011-2014

Obtained a 2:1. Undertook two research projects in my final year, including a technical-based electroencephalography study in Psychology.

Lancaster Royal Grammar School, 2005-2011

Obtained an 'A' grade in History, and 'B' grades in Chemistry, French, Drama and General Studies A-Levels. Gained 12 GCSEs A*-C, including English Literature (A*), English Language (A) and Maths (A).

Professional Affiliations:

- > British Psychological Society, with a title of MBPsS. Part of the Division of Occupational Psychology.
- ➤ British Computing Society, with the title of MBCS. Member of additional Specialist Groups including Software Process Improvement Network, Software Practice Advancement, Agile Methods, Financial Services and Advanced Programming.

Additional Information & Interests

- > I run a variety of game servers for personal use with friends, and enjoy administering my own physical and cloud servers.
- Computer enthusiast who lives for building my own machines.
- Avid football fan, both playing and watching.
- > I enjoy playing a variety of instruments in my spare time, especially the piano.
- > Treasurer and committee member of the University's trampolining team for two years.
- > British Gymnastics' qualified judge, and have judged at national competitions to an elite level.
- > Received Green Colours from Kent Sport for the administrative service I provided to the club.